eyebuydirect.com 2012-05-26

# Privacy Policy | Learn | Mens Womens Fashion | EyeBuyDirect.com

Privacy Policy

EyeBuyDirect takes the security and privacy of you personal information very seriously. We will not trade, sell, or rent your personally identifiable information.

EyeBuyDirect.com Privacy Policy

We are strongly committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information. The policies below are applicable to the EyeBuyDirect.com website ("Website") produced and maintained by EyeBuyDirect, Inc. (collectively "EyeBuyDirect" or "we", "us", or "our"). We have established this security and privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") to let you know the kinds of personal information we may gather during your visit to the Website, why we gather your information, what we use your personal information for, when we might disclose your personal information, and how you can manage your personal information.

Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy apply only to information gathered through this Web Site and, where applicable, through this Web Site's Customer Service Department in connection with this Web Site, and do not necessarily reflect our practices with respect to information gathered through other Web sites that we operate or through other off-line means.

By visiting our Website, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Website. We reserve the right to modify or amend the terms of our Privacy Policy from time to time without notice. Your continued use of our Website and our affiliate sites following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or don't see your concerns addressed here, you should contact us by email at eyecare@eyebuydirect.com.

What Information About Me Is Collected and Stored?

EyeBuyDirect adheres to the highest standards of ethical practices in all of our operations and is dedicated to protecting the privacy of all visitors to our Website. Our privacy policy is simple: Except as disclosed below, we don't sell, barter, give away, or rent your personal information to any company outside of EyeBuyDirect. One of the basic principles we've tried to follow in designing this Website is that we ask for only the information we need to provide the service you've requested. As a result, what information we collect and store depends almost entirely on how you choose to make use of our Website and our services.

Personal Information

We collect and store information that you enter into this Web Site or that you provide through our Customer Service Department. For example, when you open an account or place an order, we collect and store some or all of the following information that you provide: name, billing address, shipping address, email address, telephone number, and credit card number and expiration date. This information is used to provide the products and services that you have ordered or requested, to process and ship orders, to send order and shipping confirmations and to provide customer service. Registration may also be required and Personal Information may also be collected in certain portions of the Website in which you specifically and knowingly provide such information, e.g. community postings (i.e., chat or bulletin boards), suggestions, or customer service requests. Some of this information also may be used to contact you about sales, new products, special offers, and new site features, unless you have opted to not receive promotional communications in connection with this Web Site.

Anonymous Information

Through your use of the Website, we may also gather certain information that does not identify you individually ("Anonymous Information"). Generally, this information is collected through "traffic data". We collect and store certain other information automatically whenever you interact with this Web Site. For example, we collect your IP address, browser information and reference site domain name every time you visit this Web Site. We also collect information regarding customer traffic patterns and site usage. This information is used to analyze and improve this Web Site and to provide our customers with a fulfilling shopping experience.

Use of Cookies and Spyware

We never use or install spyware on your computer, nor do we use spyware to retrieve information from your computer.

Also, like many Web sites, we use "cookies", which are files stored on your computer's hard drive by your browser. Cookies help us to identify account holders and to optimize their shopping experience. Cookies also allow us to hold selections in a shopping cart when a user leaves this Web Site without checking out and send you reminder e-mail about your shopping orders and other shopping opportunities. Most browsers accept cookies automatically but allow you to disable them. We recommend that you leave cookies "turned on" so that we can offer you a better shopping experience on this Web Site. You may occasionally get Cookies from companies advertising on our behalf. We do not control these Cookies, and these Cookies are not subject to our Cookie policy.

We also may collect and store information about you that we receive from other sources, to enable us to update and correct the information contained in our database and to provide product recommendations and special offers that we think will interest you and, if you have agreed to receive e-mail from us, send you reminders about shopping opportunities.

Newsletters

We collect e-mail addresses of all users who subscribe to our weekly newsletter. Except to our third party agents (as described below), this information is not shared with any third parties for any purposes. Anyone who no longer wishes to receive this newsletter can, at any time, follow the "Unsubscribe" instructions located within each newsletter.

Is Information Collected From Children?

We do not sell or ship any items ordered through this Web Site directly to anyone who we know to be under the age of 13, nor do we collect any personal information from anyone who we know to be under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, you should use this Web Site only with the involvement of a parent or guardian and should not submit any personal information to us. Our Website is not intentionally targeted to children under the age of 13. Children under the age of 13 should not use our Website without obtaining prior parental consent.

How We Use Your Information?

Except as disclosed in this Security and Privacy Policy, we do not use or disclose information about your individual visits to our Website or your Personal Information collected online to any companies not affiliated with us. If we propose to permit any use of your Personal Information, you will be provided an opportunity to instruct us not to allow such contact.

Customer Service and Feedback

We may use your Personal Information to fulfill orders, provide customer service, track your compliance with the Website's rules and regulations, or for editorial and feedback purposes (to the extent that is explained when you provide the information). In the event we plan to publicly post any of your Personal Information on a Website (as, for instance, a letter), you are provided prior notification of such posting and given the option of preventing such posting.

Use of Anonymous Information

We use Anonymous Information to help us determine how people use parts of the Website and who our readers are so we can improve our Website and ensure that it is as appealing as we can make it for as many people as possible. We also use Anonymous Information to provide statistical "ratings" information in aggregated form to our partners and other third parties about how our users collectively use our website. We may also use or share Anonymous Information (or other information, other than Personal Information) in any other manner that we deem appropriate or necessary.

Third-party Agents

We occasionally have third party agents, subsidiaries, affiliates and partners that perform functions on our behalf, such as marketing, analytics, credit card processing, shipping or stocking orders, providing customer service, fraud protection etc. These entities have access to the Personal Information needed to perform their functions and are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of that Personal Information. They are restricted from using, selling, distributing or altering this data in any way other than to provide the requested services to the Website.

Transactional partners

We may share non-personal information with our partners and others from time to time. Examples of such non-personal information include the number of users who visited this Web Site during a specific time period or purchased a specific product through this Web Site. This information generally is shared in an aggregated form.

Emergency Situations

We may also use or disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on us or the Website; (b) protect and defend the our rights or property, the Website or our users, and (c) act under emergency circumstances to protect the personal safety of us, our affiliates, agents, or the users of the Website or the public.

What Steps Are Taken To Keep Personal Information Secure?

The importance of security for all Personal Information associated with you is of utmost concern to us. We exercise great care in providing secure transmission of your information from your PC to our servers. Personal Information collected by our websites is stored in secure operating environments that are not available to the public. In many instances, such as in the case of credit card numbers and all on-line purchases, the Personal Information is encrypted before you conduct your transaction. Only those employees who need access to your Personal Information in order to do their jobs are allowed access, each having signed confidentiality agreements. Any employee who violates our privacy and/or security policies is subject to disciplinary action, including possible termination and civil and/or criminal prosecution.

To protect the security of your information during transmission, we use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. Most browsers will give a visual indication of when your connection is secure. For example, Internet Explorer will show a padlock icon in the lower right of the browser window. If you place an order through this Web Site, you will be asked to set up an account and provide an email address and password. You must provide an appropriate email address and password in order to access account information. In order to help protect your personal information further, you should be careful about providing your password to others. If you wish to cancel your password, or if you become aware of any loss, theft or unauthorized use of your password, please contact this Web Site's Customer Service Department by email at eyecare@eyebuydirect.com

While we try our best to safeguard your Personal Information once we receive it, no transmission of data over the Internet or any other public network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

What Happens When I Link To or From Another Web Site?

This Web Site may contain links to other Web sites operated by EyeBuyDirect, affiliates of EyeBuyDirect or third parties. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy for EyeBuyDirect.com do not apply to information gathered through these other Web sites. These other sites may also send their own cookies to you and collect your data or solicit your personal information. Always be aware of where you end up. We are not responsible for the actions and privacy policies of third parties and other websites. We encourage you to be aware of when you leave this Web Site and to read the privacy policies of each and every Web site that you visit.

What About Contests and Sweepstakes?

When we run a contest or sweepstakes relating to this Web Site, it will be accompanied by a set of rules. The rules for each contest/sweepstakes will specify how the information gathered from you for entry will be used and disclosed, if it is different than as described in this Privacy Policy. Personal Information will be collected only if you voluntarily submit it to our sponsors or us.

Public Areas, Chat Rooms and Newsgroups

Please remember that any information you share in public areas, such as message boards or feedback sections, becomes public, and therefore this Privacy Policy does not apply to any information you choose to make public. Please be careful about what you disclose and do not post any Personal Information that you expect to keep private.

Governing Law/Assignment

The EyeBuyDirect.com website is published in the United States and is intended for users from the United States. U. S. law shall govern in any and all disputes, including privacy or defamation issues or otherwise.

We may change its ownership or corporate organization while providing the website and services. As a result, please be aware that we may transfer your information to another company that is affiliated with us or with which we have merged. Under such circumstances EyeBuyDirect would to the extent possible require the acquiring party to follow the practices described in this Privacy Policy, as it may be amended from time to time.

Changes to This Policy

We are committed to maintaining its position as a premier Website on the Internet. As our Website continues to develop, we may add new services and features to our Website. In the event that these additions affect our Privacy Policy, this document will be updated appropriately. We will post those changes prominently so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we will disclose it to anyone. We do, however, recommend that you read this Privacy Policy each time you use our website in case you missed our notice of changes to the Privacy Policy.

Opt-Out and Correction Procedures

You may always opt-out of receiving future e-mail messages and newsletters. We provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about you. There are several ways in which you can tell us whether or not you want to receive promotional communications from EyeBuyDirect.com. When you set up an account, or click on "Manage Your Account" within the Help Desk area, or place an order, you will have an opportunity to make your selections in this regard. You also will have an opportunity to change these selections by following the "unsubscribe" or "preference center" instructions contained in the promotional emails we send you. We also permit you to correct or update Personal Information that you have previously provided to us. To do so, you can access, correct and update certain personal information that you have provided to us by clicking on "Manage Your Account" within the Help Desk area of this Web Site.

Who do I talk to if I have more questions?

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to the EyeBuyDirect.com Customer Service email to [eyecare@eyebuydirect.com](mailto:eyecare@eyebuydirect.com).
